YAKINI ARUMUGA KANI

South Jordan, Utah 84095

Phone: 508 494 3722 | Email: yakinilatha09@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yakini-arumuga-kani-84265464/ | GitHub: https://github.com/YakiniA | Portfolio: https://yakinia.github.io/ReactPortfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with prior experience in testing. A creative, passionate team player and web developer who can collaborate with other team members to accomplish the project goals. Known for accountability, dedication, and commitment to meet deadlines, and uneffaced when challenged with complex problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Handlebars, React, AJAX

Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Node, MVC

Testing Tools: Chrome Developer Tools, JMeter, Selenium, JUnit, SOAPUI

Certifications: ISTQB CTFL certified tester

RECENT PROJECTS

The Fight Club

github.com/AtimaB/The-Fight-Club | the-fight-club.herokuapp.com/

- Full stack fighting game app with support for two players with real-time score tracking, and result display. Lead a three member team to create the full application while helping the team to resolve critical backend issues in Sequelize.
- Technologies Used: Node, Express, Socket.io, Handlebars, Sequelize

Employee Directory

github.com/YakiniA/19-React-EmployeeDirectory | yakinia.github.io/19-React-EmployeeDirectory/

- The application is based on creating an employee directory with React. The user can view the entire employee directory at once and can filter the employees based on name, email and phone.
- Technologies Used: React

Shifty Planner

github.com/Eelektrick/Shifty-Planner | shifty-planner.herokuapp.com/

- Shift management and timekeeping system with a focus on the needs of first responders. As an employee, it lets the user select the shift to trade. Once trade is done, it will be notified by email. The other users can either `Propose/Reject`. The same will be notified and at last swapping of shifts being done.
- Technologies Used : React, Express, Node, MongoDB

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

FRUGAL TESTING INC

Remote

Performance Test Engineer

2019 - 2020

Performance Projects: Money On Mobile, Learnwise, CRC, Impuesto

Collaborated with the team to solve complex JMeter correlation, and scripting challenges to deliver critical load testing projects on-time. Successfully uncovered five critical load testing defects by analyzing data in NewRelic, Loggly and other monitoring tools. Delivered meaningful load testing reports to the customer providing actionable insights into the application performance.

Manual Testing Projects: Middle East Corporate, Zoom

Improved the quality of the application by testing, verifying and validating the functionality and user stories across a broad variety of devices, operating systems, browsers, and platforms. Increased the test coverage of the applications through creative test design and exploratory testing and reduced the production lead of functional defects for every release.

COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS

Chennai, India

Programmer Analyst

2011 - 2013

Developed both Customer and Merchant applications using Java. Improved the unit test coverage of the existing Java application by applying various test design techniques such as boundary value analysis, decision table, and state transition. Executed system level tests using Rest Client and SOAPUI. Executing and reporting done after the test run.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

FOUNDER 2014 - 2018

Worked on opening an ECommerce store to sell party supply items online. Also involved in performing SEO to boost up the sales and did promotion on social media sites including facebook, pinterest.

EDUCATION

University Of Utah
Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Crescent Engineering CollegeBachelors in Engineering